There we go. Okay.
I was just going to ask Abby to get the recording going. So,
we
are recording
07:04.
I'll call the meeting to order.
Next on the agenda is roll call and seating of alternates.
So I see an creme is here.
Scott
person is here.
Steve Nelson
is here.
Lee Ann Hutchinson
I do not see online and she was expected to
to not be here so I will see Susan England
for Leanne.
And I am here, then as well.
So Abby, that has Leanne,
Anne Blanchard and Kevin Arsen not
present this evening.
Moving on to item three, addition or changes to the agenda.
Does anybody have any additions or changes?
>> Mr. Chairman for the record Mark Brandt's counsel to the commission you may have a change but we'll see how it evolves.
Right now you have on your agenda the modification of the DB special permit but my understanding is that
Mr. Beebe is
amending his application to be a class A kennel which is not a special permit and therefore does not require a public hearing.
You haven't advertised a public hearing for that application
but you should be okay with that and only the thing is while I have the attention to the
commission I just want to introduce Andrew Moran.
Andrew just joined our firm
and has just graduated
from law school
and we are confident we'll pass the bar when we get the results next Friday. But he'll be attending lots of commission meetings to sort of
see what it is we do. So Andrew is just listening in on us to see what's happening. Okay,
>> very good. And just so you know, Mark, it sounds like there's a little bit of a bandwidth issue coming. You do cut out now and then. Think we're able to get
the
intent of what you were saying there, and especially good news on the
application
for a Class A kennel
not being a special permit.
I was going to change
the thing to approval of special permit for a kennel at 241 Route 6. Now I guess
I will change it to approval of permit for a kennel at 241
Route 6.
So
Abby will just get rid of the words from between of
and permit
on the first action item and
that will be the only change that I have
to the agenda.
And
thanks for that timely input, Mark. When
we were looking through our regulations this morning,
Jim thought it was
not a special permit, but we talked ourselves into it and that we thought we had a clever way of getting out of the public hearing. So you saved the day by making us just right. Thanks for attending.
If there are no other
changes to the agenda,
call on the commission
to you. All
in favor of the changes discussed
say aye.
Aye.
Any
opposed?
Any abstain?
Okay, so that motion carries five-zero-zero.
Any public comment on anything
that's not on the agenda?
And I don't think there's probably anybody else here for that, but
now's the time if there's a public comment.
Okay, hearing none, we'll move down to old business.
And the first
item of old business
is,
Scott your permit for the type A kennel at 241 Route 6?
So if you can run us through what's changed from the last time. I was looking
online just before I got on for the meeting and I did not see
the updated form
that we had discussed.
So the other commission members
are not aware of your changes, so now's a good time to let us know
what
you got planned there.
>> So
after our meeting this morning, we realized that we
didn't need the
commercial kennel type C,
and we actually need the commercial
kennel type A license.
So I'm looking to get permission to continue to run my business under the commercial kennel type A license
with the opportunity to come in front of the board in the future
and go for my type C license.
>> Okay,
that
sounds good. And Jim,
how about running us through where we stand on the
appropriate portions of the application there?
>> Sure. Would you like me to run through the checklist?
>> Not
in detail. If you can just update us on those couple of things that we did not have checked off before our meeting today when we were just making sure we had everything ready
to go.
>> Okay, I mean, spoke about lighting and there is some
limited
flood lighting
for
customers.
It does not leave the
site.
Scott's operation is largely in
daylight hours. Obviously, winter
evening encroaches,
but apparently what he has has been sufficient.
I did ask the fire marshal for comment. They did not hear from him.
So
should the
commission choose to act on the application,
we could certainly
put a condition
in that in approval if that's the way they go,
allowing for any modifications
required by the fire marshal.
There was discussion about
heating and cooling and
what it came down to was
there are
basically we're talking about pretty tough dough huts and
they're just not in bitter cold, they're just not taken out into the heat, they're taken care of.
It really is not an issue,
doesn't appear to be an issue under state
regulations either.
Other than that, I don't recall any changes.
Just got clarification on really the number of dogs that will
be on-site.
I believe Scott's original
letter
alluded to the number of dogs are there over the course of the day.
And in reality, we regulate the number of dogs that are there at any given point in time.
The maximum being, I believe 10 under the type A.
And
seems to operate under
those parameters.
That's about all I have as far as updating.
>> Okay.
What I'd like to do in
Abby, if you can allow me to share my screen, I just want to go through with the commission members
the difference between the
Class A kennel and the Class C kennel
so we can all see why
we're going to be successful
here tonight, at least a
better shot at it than we did before.
You should have permission now. Okay,
>> thank you.
Okay, so hopefully everybody can see our kennel regulations on the screen now.
Yep. And
so,
you know, we looked through the definitions last time we didn't really talk about the type A kennel,
but essentially it's designed for, used to accommodate 10 or fewer dogs.
And
when we were
talking to
Scott Beebe,
you know, he sometimes has up to 20 dogs there a day to do the one hour
training sessions.
My take on the Type A kennel is that if he is boarding less than 10 dogs during the day and he's not boarding any of them overnight,
even though he's got people that bring their dog in for an hour, have a lesson, take the dog away,
I didn't think that fit in that number and I was satisfied
that
he met the requirements
with the type A kennel
by boarding
fewer than 10 dogs.
So that's
the difference
there.
Last week, we went over the general requirements
and so I'm not going to go over those again because if he complied with them for a type C kennel,
he certainly is in compliance for type A.
But then we came down to
the specifics for the type A kennel.
And
our
regulations, and maybe that's a typo that needs fixed, special permitted uses
talks about
kennel, limited commercial, all these things here.
But there was only three requirements
for the type A kennel
permitted in all use districts except the flood prone district. And we saw that it wasn't there.
Minimum lot size three acres. He's got like 200 acres out there that he's
using.
And the minimum frontage rear sideline
to the doghouse pin or run, you know, she'll be at least 75 feet. And he's,
you know, got a couple of 100 feet there at least.
So
that's
the type A as opposed to
the type B
for the type C
where we got into the requirement that the indoor housing facilities that comply with state registered commercial kennels be provided.
So we
were working hard on trying to figure out if there was a way to meet the indoor kennel facilities.
There's not at this point because he's got five kennels in the barn
instead of the 20 that he would have to have.
And that's why when we decided to go the route of the Class A kennel,
that seemed to
make it fairly easy at that point to go in compliance with the regulations.
So that's all that. We'll go back up and
take a quick look at
the application procedure
and all the plans and data called for in the Planning and Zoning Commission application form have been submitted,
including his
check for
the special permit.
If this is not the special permit, Jim,
you can adjudicate whether or not we owe Scott any money back on that.
The plot plan, same plan picture that we were looking at last meeting,
The detailed description of proposed operations
that is online. Is there anybody who didn't get a chance to
take a look at that?
Thought that was a good write up that told us what he wanted to do.
Other information the commission deems appropriate. If there's anything there, we could talk about it
It is fee for $65
And
maybe that's just the fee to the town whether or not it's a special permit, I don't know. We'll
hash our way through that, that's not the big part of the deal.
So,
this point, you know,
I would open the floor to the commission members to ask
Scott
Bebe if
you have any questions or
comments on
his application.
>> I've read it all, I've read all the different
classifications
and I believe that that's just, was a good thing to do the type A.
>> Okay.
Anybody at all have any questions for the applicant?
>> Mr. Chairman, just for the record, Mark Reince, there is a site plan that depicts what is happening there, what is proposed?
>> Yes,
there is,
and we talked this morning about making sure that that actually got filed this time.
Okay, all right, good.
>> So
if there are no other questions for the applicant,
I'm looking for somebody to make a motion concerning the application.
And I guess
to speed up the process, I'll make a motion to approve the application for a type A kennel at 241
Route 6.
I'll second that. Thank you, Scott.
Any
discussion on the application?
Do
you need any conditions?
I
>> the only condition is that I'm aware of is it understood that the instrument
I know you mentioned that there were
five
indoor kennels
is that a limit? Could it be up to 10?
As long as you're clear what you're approving that's all I care about. So
>> at this point he has five kennels in the barn
and I think it was six outdoor
kennels.
And so that gets him up to the facility to handle at least 10 dogs now.
As Mr. Beebe stated when we came on, he he would like at some point in the future to upgrade the barn or
at least have the opportunity to upgrade the barn for a type C kennel,
but does not have those indoor kennel facilities at this point.
And so
consider that he's got 11
kennels.
>> But what's it being approved now?
Yes.
Okay,
do want to clarify, should the motion clarify that that's what's being approved now?
>> Well,
the motion was
specific that it was a type A dental.
The
condition of approval would be that we
continue to pursue
the approval by the fire marshal.
And that is the only outstanding
condition
of approval that
I think is appropriate for tonight.
Anything else attorney brands.
>> As long as it's clear what, how many dogs or how many kennels you're
Up to 10. Improving.
>> Up to 10. That's fine. Up to 10. And he's got the facilities to handle that matter.
>> Chairman Larson. Good enough, thank you. There's been discussion about the fire marshals
weighing in on it, but I didn't really see it make its
way into that motion as a condition. It was merely
discussed
as
I heard it. Okay,
>> good point.
And let me ask you back, Jim,
with this being a type A kennel
and not having to go through the
Heinz fifty seven questionnaire
of all the questions there, do
we need the fire marshal's approval still?
And it might be because it's such a lengthy driveway.
I don't know.
>> No, I would say there's no specific requirement.
It's just,
you know, it's no,
if it's not a special permit, then I don't see it falling
under it
as an absolute requirement.
But he
could certainly be added as a recommendation.
>> Okay.
And I think
I will allow you to follow-up
with the fire marshal.
Will not amend
the motion to include
the fire marshal on that. If
the fire marshal thinks we need to have a bigger turnaround space or something like that, I'm sure that
Mr. Beebe would be happy to
comply with that.
He's trying to run a good facility out there.
And I'm sure that
we'll get there. If not, we'll
take care of that when he comes back with his class C
kennel because then it will be a requirement.
Any last discussion?
Okay,
we'll go call for a roll call vote.
Anne?
Aye.
>> Scott. Aye.
Steve.
Aye.
Susan. Aye.
And I vote aye as well. The motion passes
500.
Congratulations
Mr. Beebe.
>> Thank you all. I appreciate all the work and help to get here tonight.
Thank you.
>> So I think Jim, you'll be ready to sign that form that
Scott needs here
like tomorrow? Is there anything you need before that happens?
No, I'm fine. Okay, very
>> good.
So that completes
the first item
under old business.
We're going to move on to item
B under old business, review requests for proposals for preparation
of an affordable housing plan.
And so
all the commission members should have gotten,
we got three proposals
that
came in.
One was unexpected,
didn't know about it until we went there to open them up on September
1.
The other one was from a fellow named
Don Poland.
Both of those two
submittals were very professionally done and
they look very good. The
third
submittal that we got was from
Bill Warner
and while the first two came in at
$15,000
Bill Warner's came in at 6,900.
So,
and if you, does anybody have any comments
on
the write ups that we looked through?
>> I
reviewed all three
was should I tell you who I'm most comfortable with or is that not appropriate now? Nope, this is a good time to Okay,
read all three and both
the Gorman in York
and the SLR
were very impressive,
very detailed.
I was actually not comfortable with the Gorman in York application
partially because it seemed to be full of planning jargon,
which was hard to
pick apart and understand what they were saying. It wasn't really written in
plain English, which made me concerned,
especially when they did the public presentation, how clear
it was and if they were just going to stand up there and
rattle dazzle people. And the other thing I didn't like about it was their payment plan,
which was
every month you would pay them a set amount of $3,000
It wasn't tied into completion
of the various tasks.
I have found in the past it's
easier
and you have more control over managing the contract
if everything is tied into
production
of a document or completion of a task.
Bill Warner's was not as professionally done or as razzle dazzle as the others,
but what I have worked with him and the commission has worked with him for probably close to twenty years
on the production of two plans of development
and
also when he was our planning
our zoning agent and and I found that he was very easy to work with. He was very familiar with the different trends
And just before I left the commission was when we were completing the latest plan of conservation development.
He alerted us all to the whole issue of the affordable housing and the fact that Andover
was currently facing a, he
didn't call it a crisis, crisis is my word,
that we were one of the older towns and there was a whole issue of,
because of the way the housing stock had been developed and the zoning had been developed,
the problems that this town was facing. He was really
present in what's going on. So I'm comfortable with his work
and I know that the products that he produces are high quality.
So
if I were to rank them, I would rank him first,
SLR second and Gorman you'll work third.
>> Okay,
thank you, Susan.
Anybody
else have any comments on the three proposals that we received?
>> Yeah,
I agree. I think SLR was the most professional,
the most comprehensive,
and the most complete out of the three.
I don't have any background
as you just described,
you know, with the others, but,
you know, having written a lot of proposals,
I think it, you know, it actually
included a, you know, a timeline.
It broke everything down in detail.
The other one that was professional,
I thought just provided kind of
a Rolodex of their capabilities
of who they have on their team,
but it really didn't,
it wasn't a customized solution for us
in our town, I didn't think.
SLR also had some good,
case studies in there,
like the town of Mansfield, etcetera. So I thought it was the most comprehensive
overall.
>> Okay.
It was
interesting.
Well,
it may have been an error.
But when we requested
the grant money from the state,
I did not request $15,000
so we don't have $15,000
to spend.
We did request a little bit more than Bill has
listed there, the 6,900.
And
I guess
if we had money left over, that would
give us an opportunity
to
hire some legal service to maybe help us get
the
I think the plan is going to tell us what to go do and then we're going to be having to change our I don't think it's going to change our regulations
for us and so I'm going to need some assistance
probably after and there might be a little bit of money left over to support doing some of that.
But certainly,
you know, Bill Warner, as Susan said,
you know, wrote our last two plan of conservation and developments
and did do
the section that we've got on our website
on the incentive housing study. So I think
the reason he can do it by himself is the fact that he doesn't have a large staff
and that he
has done all the background work and he's got a pretty good idea of how to
get that to the finish line without
it being a major production.
So
I'm kind of comfortable based on his letter saying how he is uniquely qualified
there.
So
Susan,
based on your recommendation,
would you like to make a motion for the Commission to consider?
>> I
would like to make motion that the Commission
retain
the services of
William Warner
to prepare the affordable housing plan
for the town of Andover.
Second test.
>> Okay, thank you, Susan. And thank you, Scott. Any
discussion on that at this point?
Hearing none,
will call a roll call vote once again. Anne?
Aye.
>> Scott? Aye.
Steve?
Didn't hear you Steve you might be muted.
Sorry, I was on mute. Aye. Susan.
>> Aye. And I vote aye as well so the motion passes 500.
Moving right along here.
Okay, new business.
Special permit application for 23 Route 6 at Network Inc. For installation
of two
gazebos.
And I
see
Eric Network. I don't know who's behind the screen there, but
if you can
discuss with us your application there.
>> Oh,
think it was late, middle to late June, we put in a permit.
We purchased
a few big What is your name, please? My name is Eric Adelczak. I'm one of the maintenance coordinators
here at networking. I've been here thirteen years. So,
you know, I
feel like I know a little bit about the town of Andover and
yeah, I was just surprised,
I guess, how long it's taken.
We we ordered these garden barn gazebos
early
in the year, just wanted our clients to have a nice, safe outdoor area,
you know, to separate, to do in the fresh air, to get out of the sun,
COVID and everything.
Now it's pretty much the end of summer,
and know things got a little lost
somehow,
so I'm not blaming anybody.
No, just like a nice comfortable area for our clients.
That's about it, I think.
>> Garrett, do you have the ability to show us the site plan of where the gazebos are in relation to the various things I see online?
>> It's all in the permits.
It's all in the agenda
documents.
The
first one, I think it's called 6 To 921
Gazebo that's the whole.
The
whole permit
it shows the copies of the garden barn purchases.
>> But do you have that available to show to us if we allow you to share your screen?
And if not, I can call it up out of our town website.
>> Yeah, you might as well do that because
I have you on a different
laptop.
Yeah.
>> I have it here, Jay, if you want me to pull it up.
>> And
that was you, Abby? Yep. Okay. Yep, go ahead and pull it up. That would be great. You want the site plan? Yes, please. Okay. Hold on just a second.
You all can see that?
Yes.
Okay, great.
I don't want to
>> go through that, Abby. Scroll back out for a minute. This is just the checklist and
I will, so.
No,
>> I was hoping for the very bottom
thing on his application.
Oh, there you go. That'll do. There you go. Okay.
Yep. So
how about you
describing for us on there where the gazebos will actually be?
>> So we have
We have two different diseases.
One at that number one near the front parking lot.
Okay.
>> That will be a
14 by 30 foot
Gazebo.
And then number
two,
towards the back corner,
locked down, it's a 14 foot.
Still in that same picture.
Yeah, okay, I see it there.
>> Yeah,
there.
Well installed by the garden barn, they put down a crushed
stone.
It's in the,
just
scroll down to the garden barn
receipt,
you know, it says what they do for
the site prep.
We're getting a
little walkway
for wheelchairs
over to the front one.
I spoke to the fire marshal. One concern he had was
a barrier of sorts between the parking lot and the gazebo, which is definitely a good idea. I do have one other
quote that I just got on Friday.
It's for a 20 foot long,
10 by 10 post,
kind of like a
10 by 10 posts with four inch by eight inch rails.
So something you'd see like
a state park,
basically a barrier of sorts that would be in front
of those two parking spaces.
Between the parking lot and the gazebo, just in case somebody accidentally stepped on the gas instead of the grid.
There's no electrical going out there, nothing like that.
>> Okay.
And as I recall, I saw on the website that you did have
a letter from the
sanitarian
saying he approved the location for the installation of the.
>> Yeah the Eastern Highlands
that they approve that I have that in there. Okay.
The property part in there and added as much as I could.
The septic should be plenty far away from
the back of zero.
>> Okay,
go ahead and close-up your screen so we can see everybody again here.
And
when
I first heard about the application,
you know,
started asking myself
do we need to go to the commission
to have somebody put in the gazebo?
And we were
talking it over with Jim and they
had a special permit
for the facility
that's out there.
So we talked about a couple of options and then
one of the
good sides of the BB application
is it got me looking into
Chapter 21 of our regulations
which is enforcement,
But there's a paragraph in there
that talks about,
and it says,
the Commission may by resolution
permit the zoning enforcement officer
to authorize minor non substantial
deviations
for from the approved special exemption and special permits.
So
the decision for
the Commission tonight
is whether we consider this a
minor non substantial deviation
from the whole site plan that they went through to put up the facility,
know, with all the parking lot septic, all that goes with it.
If we did
determine
that it is a
substantial change,
the next paragraph in here states substantial
changes to special exemptions,
special permits, and variances
shall be treated as new applications for approval
and shall be submitted and acted upon in accordance with these regulations.
So essentially,
just like we would have done with the kennel, if he actually had an approval, we would have been forced back into
submitting a new application anyhow.
Those are the two options that we have here. We can either do a new application to put in
the two gazebos
or we can say Jim is the zoning enforcement officer
and zoning agent,
you go and handle the details of making sure that
the gazebos
fit in
the in accordance with all of our regulations.
And so with that,
I will make a motion
and this is to get us to the discussion point.
I would make a motion that we do
resolve
to
send the permit
to the zoning enforcement officer to authorize minor
non substantial deviations from the approved special exemption special permits
which we consider the gazebos to be.
Second.
>> Thank you, Steve. And so is there any discussion
on that?
I think that's a good idea.
>> Okay,
Jim, do you have any concerns about taking that approach?
>> I don't. I mean, I essentially traded very similar to a special permit, walked through the checklist.
I did actually,
I have a comment from the fire marshal saying that he will be signing off on it.
Okay. I have no physical sign off,
I have a memo that's actually, I was copied
a memo from fire marshal to the building office building official
who was checking up on the status of it.
And he says he I
talked to the manager and he explained the plan for the barrier.
Obviously he was okay with it.
That's pretty much all I have. Okay.
>> So with that
in mind,
I'll call for a vote. Mr. Chairman, for the record.
Ahead, Attorney Branch.
>> Just
two
items for the record Mark Brantz.
Didn't have the benefit of seeing the plans in advance,
are the
dimensions of these structures clear? Because what I saw on screen I did not see dimensions.
Are dimensions on the plan?
The applicant just stated, he
just said what he told you verbally what dimensions.
Yes they're all in the permit. They were, is that on the plan?
Yes Jim it is, okay the only other thing is
I'm
not sure which
language Mr. Chairman you're reading from in terms of minor non substantial changes,
but I do notice that section 23.1
special permit exception requirement says the Commission may waive the requirement for special permit
exception where it finds that one special permit exception use is being substantive for another similar use to the same lot
etc.
The new use will require no greater parking or loading than the original, that's probably the case here. The new use should
entail no exterior
change to the building or site.
Isn't this changing the exterior of the building or
site?
No.
>> But sure
sure it is. I mean you're adding two. How
>> can two
gazebos not be changing the exterior of the of the site?
Oh the site yeah the site.
It's a building, there are two buildings.
Attorney branch
>> They made the definition for buildings.
My
only concern is that I don't want somebody
else to come back and say well you let other people add buildings to a special permit without a public hearing or anything why can't I?
I mean it's the same they seem fairly minor it's not a question whether it's a good use or a bad use it's just a matter of what the right procedure is.
So the paragraph that I was Was there another section you wrote we can't Mr. Chairman?
21Point7
Charlie.
Let's
see.
Correct.
211Point2
You're
breaking up. One.
I'd be happy to read it.
>> I guess that's a question I mean when I look at 23 I see exterior changes I see what you're looking at and the question is whether adding two buildings is not unsubstantial.
I think you have some discretion here just like I say my worry as your attorney is always that one that you
know what you're approving that's always number one of my concern that you know where these are going and how big they are
and what they're going to be used for
as
long as you're clear on that as long as the application materials are clear on that that's fine
and then the procedure is the correct procedure.
So I
leave it to you. Okay And
>> I am always
concerned about the precedent we set with every decision
that we make.
But I was comfortable looking at this from the perspective of
if he were putting up a small shed,
would we expect the commission to act on that?
And certainly there's some place where
we would draw the line.
And I know at least one of these gazebos was fairly significantly sized. It's not
small like what we would put in our backyard, good size.
But I thought that
I was comfortable
with having the commission vote on was that
a
minor non substantial deviation
from what we would consider a special permit application.
And I thought that was a
reasonable use of our procedures to
get to the
desired outcome.
There's
a couple of different paths we could have got there. I'm not sure one is any better than the other, but this is the one I chose to because
you pointed me into this chapter to study up on the BB application.
So I'm a lot smarter on this chapter now.
So all that having been said,
I am comfortable with the motion.
It
is up to the Commission to decide
whether the Commission is comfortable with the motion.
And with that, I'll call for a vote
at this point
if there's no other discussion.
Hearing none,
call for vote, Anne?
Aye.
Scott? Aye. Steve?
Susan?
Aye.
>> And I vote aye as well. The motion passes five-zero-zero.
Thank you.
>> Eric,
you can get with
Jim and
finish up
what we've got there.
If it comes back to haunt me, if somebody gets us in trouble with a follow on application, I guess we'll cross that bridge when we get there.
But I thought I was
doing okay by looking at the regulations and getting something to standardize.
Thanks, appreciate the time.
>> Okay,
item of new business is the approval of our annual report.
And
I did get your feedback.
So here's our
annual report. You've all had a chance
to read through that.
Got two people pointed out one typo in there. I corrected that.
And so
I would like to make a motion that the Planning and Zoning Commission annual report be approved for forwarding to
the Board of Select.
I second it.
>> Thank you, Anne.
Any discussion on the
report?
Hearing none, call for vote, Anne.
Aye.
>> Scott. Aye.
Steve. Aye.
Susan.
Aye.
And I vote aye as well. The motion passes
500.
Next item up is the approval of the minutes from 08/16/2021.
Mr. Chairman, do need me to remain?
>> Say again? Do you want
me to
say I to stay unless you've
got further instruction for your
new member of the firm there? No, I
>> think the hard stuff is taken care of. I agree and I appreciate you showing up tonight. Thank you very much for your help. All right, thank you Mr. Chairman, good to see all of you. Good night. Good night.
Good night.
>> Okay, I'd like to make a motion to approve the regular meeting minutes of 08/16/2021.
So moved.
Okay, Scott, is there a second?
Second.
>> Thank you, Susan. Any discussion on those minutes?
And I had
no comments on there.
I thought for Abby's first
go at
the meeting minutes, she did an exceptionally fine job.
Actually, for any go at the meeting minutes, I thought that was an exceptionally fine job,
not just the first go. So well done, Abby. Thank you.
Okay, hearing no comments, call for a vote. Anne?
Aye.
Sky. Aye.
Steve.
Since I was not in attendance I will abstain.
>> Okay, and I vote aye as well. So,
the motion carries four zero one
with Steve Nelson abstaining.
Next
item up is
correspondence.
Jim, any correspondence there? No.
Okay.
Moving on to administrative reports enforcement actions.
>> At
the last meeting, I indicated I was going to be sending a letter to Steve Barnett,
owner of the property at
And Something Route 6. I did, I have not heard from him. I will
contact him in person.
Can't really follow-up
with
a cease and desist because I have to be a little more specific as to what I'm expecting to do.
To remind the commission, there was a
number of approvals for the particular parcel
over the years for special permits to operate
a number of different operations. I'm just gonna have to clarify
where he is in violation. And I think primarily it's junk.
And I will do that.
I will have to find him.
Actually, didn't call him. I did not call him. I relied on the letter and did not hear from him.
So I'm gonna follow-up on that.
Other than that,
just administratively,
a fair amount of activity, people looking at lots, looking at to do various things with parcels that's rather time consuming.
And we are
transitioning to
an electronic permitting system, which is
probably going be very helpful over time. But like anything else, just takes a little bit of getting used to.
But it's interesting because
we're such a small town and people
aren't there at the same time.
So I think this
permitting system is going to be a benefit
in that respect, hopefully.
Changes stuff.
I believe the town has
authorized
and is advertising
for an individual to work in the office twenty hours per week.
And hopefully that will happen soon. In the interim, we do have somebody working there.
Kathy Lund who worked there for seventeen
years
and came back
to help out for a short period of time. So we're fortunate in that respect.
One other thing I just want to touch upon is, know, some inquiries about
a commercial
parcel on Route 6
and
a number of inquiries that would involve
application
of the floating zone that the commission
adopted.
I
think it's a great idea and I
think it's envisioned
as pretty complicated
for a project,
a single parcel.
Just passing that on as an observation, that's all.
Just a reminder or
let people know who weren't around,
the Commission adopted a floating zone,
which it's
hard to explain a floating zone, but essentially it's
placed over a certain
parcel of land, a defined parcel of land. It's a zone change.
And then a special permit
is applied for.
The regulation allows for a lot of flexibility, allows mixed use,
which isn't allowed elsewhere in our regs.
Just reporting on what's happening out there.
Just to kind of see what's coming in.
And that's all I have.
Okay,
any questions for Jim?
What parcel is that Jim?
>> The old bus property,
big house on Route 6.
Actually it's the one with the airplane on the back on Hutchinson Road. Oh yeah, yeah. It's running just on Hutchinson Road as well.
>> That's the one that they're
wondering about the floating zone?
>> Well,
people had inquired that, well, one of them wouldn't need it, but one of them I thought would require the floating zone. And I think it was kind of scary.
And this is the White Tavern property, isn't it?
>> Yes.
Yeah, okay.
And
it's an
interesting parcel.
It's got a number of outbuildings. It's a beautiful old
house that is
an asset to the town. And it's also got frontage on Hutchinson, which I think is,
I worry about development on 6 and more
curb cuts, etcetera, or more traffic directly off 6.
So I have. Okay.
>> Moving on to item 10, commission discussion miscellaneous.
Anybody got anything they think we should be talking about tonight.
>> I'm
wondering if we're going to put the
frontage
and
flood zone.
Building in the flood zone on our agenda at some point.
I think that we just need to put it on there and don't
take it off Jed.
>> Okay, yeah, well, and there's probably other changes,
that we're
racking up a list of them.
Was just reluctant to
schedule the public hearing to do
those couple of changes. I was hoping to piggyback that on to
some other public hearing with other changes that we had coming out of
the housing study, but
we'll see. I've got
what I think those changes need to be.
I just need to get the
most recent updated word version of the
regulation so I can update it and show you the changes
and that sort of thing.
We can put that and carry it forward. I honestly thought that we would not get done with tonight's meeting
quite so early. I thought it was going go a little longer
than the
last minute. It
fell into place and became rather
a lot easier than I was expecting.
So,
that's that. I'm not sure how busy we're going to be with the incentive housing study coming up and
how much work we've got to do on that, but I would expect that that might get started at the next meeting, too.
I would like to,
any other topics other than Scott's
continuing to try and hold me honest
to making those changes, I said I would.
I did want to make
a couple of
lessons learned from the special permit
modification
process,
and we hit it a little bit with
the gazebo
that
I guess there's a couple of places we could have looked for guidance on that,
but to modify
an application
or to modify a special permit, you've got two choices. We can either, it's minor and we turn it over to Jim or we start a new application.
What
we had with
you know, the BB application
was
was approved by the Commission,
his application,
and
the application had a pretty extensive set of drawings with it to build a nice kennel and all that stuff
after he got approval,
one, he didn't file
the final documents with the town hall, town clerk,
and then he didn't build the kennel that was authorized in there.
Either of those
would have invalidated
the special permit. So that's how we got to the point where
it was not a modification of a special permit.
There was no special permit to modify because he didn't file it, then he didn't comply with it. And so that
took us a while to get through the facts of
we were essentially starting over with a new permit there.
I think there might be some confusion too, I just wanted to mention it, that when we use a special permit,
there might be some thought that
the regulations don't apply because we're bringing it to the Commission. The Commission can do whatever they want.
And that's not true either. The
special permit
really,
you know, the significance of that is that buys us into holding a public hearing to get
more information from the public on
the permit.
It doesn't
allow us to not comply with any of the regulations or any of that kind of stuff. So we have to comply with all the regulations, but we also have to hold a public hearing and that's
a significance of the special permit piece of it.
So anyhow, I'm a lot clearer on that now. That might not be absolutely clear to all of you guys, but we'll keep talking about it each time we go through one of those and
make sure that
we understand that whatever we do is rooted in the regulations and that we are doing our very best to comply with those.
I
am going to look for my calendar here just so we can talk about the
next meeting I think is going to be on October
18.
And that is all I have.
So
looks like it might be a record setter for getting done early. I appreciate everybody's
help.
Anything
that I could have done to have explained the process better as we went through the applications tonight?
Okay?
And feel free to send me an email if you don't want to say you're on
the Zoom call.
But I'm always interested in how
we can
better,
you know, share what we're learning there because I know
it's taken a fair amount of time for the regulations to start making sense to me.
I think I've got a little knowledge that's dangerous
and
that's why we get attorney branch to help us out on those kinds of things from time to time.
Other than that, is there a motion to adjourn?
Motion to adjourn.
The second.
Second.
>> Okay, I think that was a
Scott motion Steve
second.
All in favor say aye. Aye.
Any opposed?
Aye.
Who opposed?
I think that was a late entry.
Yes,
it was.
>> We're here to try it again. All in favor, aye.
Aye.
Any opposed?
Okay, the motion carries
5 100.
Thank you everybody and
see you next month. Appreciate the help. Okay, bye. Bye.
Bye everyone. Good night.